# Ruby Sattar - Educator/Technical Architect

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language.

I'm a Technical Enablement Architect and a teacher in the Providence area. Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to help others achieve their technical goals and impact the future of tech resources available in underserved communities.



### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

## Postman, Remote - Technical Enablement Architect AUG 2021 - PRESENT

At Postman, I was part of the Solutions Engineering team and worked cross-functionally on multiple product squads. As a TEA, I was responsible for:

- Building and maintaining demo environments in our product, using multiple API architectural styles to use during sessions with enterprise customers.
- Collaborated with the Customer Education team regularly to produce content for our Learning Management System.
- Creating internal and external educational content regarding products.
- Implementing new integrations on a consistent basis in demo environments to ensure the latest product features were always ready to demonstrate,

# TrueMotion/CMT, Boston - Technical Support Engineer FEB 2021 - AUG 2021

TrueMotion/CMTelematics is a leading smartphone telematics platform. As a TS Engineer, I was responsible for:

- Training and onboarding customers onto the company's program management systems.
- Producing/Maintaining a customer support knowledge base and educational videos.
- Debugging customers' technical issues and documenting the process for internal teams.
- Providing escalated technical and triage support, using an incident response protocol.
- Sustaining Engineering through ongoing releases of configuration changes to the company code base.

# **STEM ENRG,** Boston - *Project Manager* SEP 2020 - APR 2021

STEM ENRG is a non-profit program for women of color. It provides opportunities to build technical projects for local community organizations. I started as a Mentee and was quickly promoted to Project manager, offering technical support, education, and leadership to a team through an Agile workflow.

#### **General Assembly, Boston -** *Engineering Fellow* JUNE 2020 - SEP 2020

At GA's Software Engineering Immersive program, I received a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and currently conducting user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.
- Collaborated on teams to build and demo applications in an Agile workflow.
- Problem-solved using industry standard development tools and documentation.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

**JSON** MongoDB **AWS** React **jQuery** Node.js SQL Express.js CSS/Scss **Jenkins** Git **Postman NoSQL** SumoLogic **RESTful API's** Jira

#### **SKILLS**

Cross-industry technology
Teamwork
Leadership
Technical Education Delivery
Trouble-shooting
Communication
Coaching
Project Management

#### **EDUCATION**

## LinkedIn Learning — Certificates

NOV 2019

HTML, CSS, SCRUM

# Florida International University, Miami — Bachelor's in Elementary Education

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Magna Cum Laude, Honors, field research in ed-tech.

# **PROJECTS**

**Enterprise Enablement "Cosmic Courses"** — Multiple Reveal.js self-serve learning modules for enterprise customers seeking to understand how to use the Postman API platform.

**Apple HIG Updates Video** — An educational video sponsored by TrueMotion to inform customers about Human Interface Guidelines changes [post-production video editing software used by TrueMotion's Creative Director]

**OverAchiever** — *A flashcard learning application* [Python, Django, React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, SCSS]

**The Holistic Educator** — *A classroom connections tracking application* [Mongoose, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, SCSS]

**Education Donation Store** — *E-Commerce Team project/application* [Mongoose, Express, React]S, Javascript, Bootstrap, SCSS]

## OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**KIPP Academy,** Boston - *Kindergarten Lead Teacher* FEB 2018 - JUNE 2020

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate to ensure students' academic success.

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum with G-Suite tech resources.
- Utilized Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction
- Implemented differentiated intervention instruction to a top-performing class of 25 families during a global pandemic.

The Mildred (BPS), Boston - Lead Teacher OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

SFPCC of Harvard, Boston - Lead Teacher AUG 2015 - MAY 2017